Thank you for putting up with me during my foray into traditional machine learning.
전통적인 머신 러닝을 배우는 동안 절 참아주셔서 감사해요
I think it was useful for us and I hope that you didn't mind it too much.
저희에게 유용했던 것 같아요 너무 불쾌하지 않으셨으면 해요
Maybe you enjoyed yourself a little bit like I did and tried out your own models too.
저처럼 비트도 즐기면서 직접 모델을 만들어 보기도 했죠
Let's just look at how they appear side by side.
나란히 있는 모습을 보시죠
We started with a random model, which came in at a somewhat shocking $341 off from the from the reality.
무작위 모델로 시작했는데 현실에서 341달러나 차이가 나더군요
And then we tried a constant model that did a whole lot better, but was still $146 wrong.
그리고 지속적인 모델을 썼는데 훨씬 잘 나왔지만 여전히 146달러가 모자랐어요
We then did some proper models, the features and and linear regression model.
그런 다음 제대로 된 모델을 만들었죠 특징과 선형 회귀 모델요
At 139 we did a whole lot better with a bag of words model, the Countvectorizer and $114.
139달러로 훨씬 더 벌었죠 단어 봉지 모델 카운트베이터라이저와 114달러로요
We were slightly disappointed that when we layered on the powerful word two vec, it came in at $115.
조금 실망스러웠던 건 강렬한 단어 2개를 겹쳤을 때 115달러가 나왔다는 거예요
You may have noticed that there were 400 dimensions of word two vec, whilst there were a thousand dimensions
두 벡이라는 단어의 400차원이란 걸 아셨을 겁니다 단어 모델에는 1,000차원이
in the bag of words model, But still, you would expect that the 400 dimensions in the word two vec
있지만 그래도 두 벡이라는 단어의 400차원은 너무 과하다고
would be just so much.
생각하실 거예요
There would be so much more signal in those vectors that you would expect better results.
그런 벡터에는 훨씬 더 많은 신호가 있어서 더 나은 결과를 기대할 수 있죠
So whilst that was a bit disappointing, we quickly made up for it.
그래서 좀 실망스러웠지만 비트를 빠르게 메꿨죠
First of all, by getting a hair better when we use support vector machines, but then random forests
우선 지원 벡터 머신을 사용할 때 조금 더 나아집니다 그런데 임의의
save the day with a nice $97 error there.
숲이 97달러짜리 오류로 문제를 해결하죠
And you know, there's there's this potential school of thought that would be to say that $97 is still
97달러가 여전히 실망스럽다는 의견도 있어요
disappointing given just predicting the the price of a product.
제품 가격을 예측한 것만으로도요
But I'll tell you something.
하지만 이건 말씀드리죠
I challenge you yourself to go in and pick some of those products and blindly try and price them.
직접 가서 제품을 골라 보고 맹목적으로 가격을 매겨 보세요
It ain't easy.
쉽지 않아요
It's surprisingly difficult.
의외로 어렵네요
You saw when we were confronted with that LED light, that we looked at that example a moment ago,
LED 라이트가 나왔을 때 보셨었죠 조금 전에 본 예제인데요
I think, and I don't know if I had seen that, I would have probably have guessed that's about $40
제가 그걸 봤는지는 모르겠지만 40달러 정도라고 생각했을 거예요
or something.
200달러 정도였어요
So, you know, it's actually surprisingly hard just given a description of something to figure out.
그래서 사실 묘사를 하는 것만으로 이해하기가 정말 어려워요
Where is this on a scale?
여긴 몇 등급이에요?
And so getting within $97 based purely on a description of some product that could be electronics,
전자 제품일 수도 있고 전자제품일 수도 있고 다른 제품일 수도 있지만
it could be an appliance, it could be any of those other automotive, of course, any of the other
97달러 이내로 좁히는 건 우리가 고른
things, the categories that we picked, it's it's not as easy as it sounds.
모든 분야에서 쉽지 않아요
And so getting within $97 of it on average across our test set is not bad at all.
테스트 세트에서 평균 97달러 이내로 들어온 건 나쁘지 않아요
Not bad at all.
나쁘지 않네요
But potentially we'll be able to do better.
하지만 더 잘할 수 있어요
We will see.
두고 봐야죠
All right.
좋아요
So well done on getting to this point.
여기까지 오느라 고생했어요
It's been a lot of fun for me.
정말 즐거운 시간이었어요
Anyway.
어쨌든요
You've tolerated me and hopefully you didn't mind it.
저를 참아주셨는데 괜찮으셨길 바라요
But fear not, the time has arrived for us to go to the frontier.
하지만 걱정 마세요 우리가 변방으로 갈 때가 왔어요
So, uh, next time we're going to be talking about solving commercial problems using frontier models,
다음에 프론티어 모델을 이용해 상업적 문제를 해결할 때는
we are then going to run that runner against GPT four mini and see how it fares.
GPT 4 미니와 함께 달리면서 성능을 확인해 보죠
And then I'm going to be brave.
그리고 용기를 낼 거예요
I'm going to set our sights high, and we are going to run our test dataset against the big guy, against
목표를 높게 잡고 이 거대한 GPT 40 맥시와 데이터 집합을
GPT four zero maxi, the full version, the frontier version from August.
시험할 겁니다 8월에 출시된 풀 버전 프런티어 버전이죠
And that's going to be a big test for us.
우리에겐 큰 시험이 될 거예요
We'll see how it does.
어떻게 될지 봐야죠
And yeah, remember, it's quite a challenge for an LLM because we're we're basically we're not going
기억하셔야 할 것은 LLM에게는 꽤나 어려운 일입니다 왜냐하면 우리는 기본적으로 어떤 훈련 데이터도 제공하지
to give it any training data.
않을 것이기 때문이죠
Unlike these traditional models where we've given them training data, we're simply going to send the
훈련 데이터를 제공했던 전통적인 모델과는 달리 테스트 데이터를 LLM에
test data to the LLM and say, given all of your worldly knowledge, how much do you think this is going
보낼 겁니다 그리고 세속적인 지식을 바탕으로 얼마나 얻을 수 있다고 생각하나요? 값어치는
to get and how much do you think it's going to be worth?
얼마나 될까요?
And that's not an easy problem to set.
설정하기 쉬운 문제는 아니죠
So in many ways, the traditional machine learning models have a big advantage that they've been trained
전통적인 머신 러닝 모델은 여러모로 큰 이점이 있어요 훈련 데이터 집합을 바탕으로
based on a training data set.
훈련했다는 점이죠
In the case of these frontier models, we're just going to give them the descriptions and say, okay,
이 개척 시대 모델의 경우 그냥 설명을 해 줄 거예요 가격
how much is this?
같은 거요
We will see how they get on in the next video.
다음 영상에서 어떻게 하는지 보죠 get it get it